<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Jatin Gupta</title>
    <link>jg7.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="jg7.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Jatin Gupta</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/jg7.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>jg7.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought Prediction</title>
      <link>jg7.github.io/project/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>jg7.github.io/project/project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The random and nonlinear nature of drought variables makes accurate drought prediction a challenging
scientific problem. The project builds a digital tool and a Machine Learning model to predict the water
scarcity in an area and compare the results of several classifiers to get the best accuracy of the prediction.
The procedure starts with getting the publicly available dataset, then fitting the dataset to different
regression classifiers and obtaining the accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hand Emoji Recognition and Generator</title>
      <link>jg7.github.io/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>jg7.github.io/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project consists of a hand gesture recognition method and emoji generator using TensorFlow
object detection API for training, filters to detect hand and Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for
training the model. Here, a database is being created of hand gestures in order to train the system.
The prediction will be based on the hand gestures and to capture the gestures to at most precision by
training for various positions of the hand movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentimental Analysis of Tweets</title>
      <link>jg7.github.io/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>jg7.github.io/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aims to analyze customer’s perspectives toward the critical to success in the marketplace. The program is using a machine-based learning approach which is more accurate for analyzing a sentiment, ogether with natural language processing techniques will be used. As a result, the program will be categorized sentiment into positive and negative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
